Thanh Le

Passionate, professional senior software engineer with strong architecture skills and the ability to learn quickly. Committed high quality, reusable, testable code and user experience that will stand the test of time. Love functional programming and open source.

Experience

3/2023 - Present Software Engineer - Recorded Future:

1/2023 - Present Lichess:

Lichess.org is a free/libre, open-source chess server powered by volunteers and donations.

- Maintainer the chess logic library: https://github.com/lichess-org/scalachess.
- Irregular contributor for its main server: https://github.com/lichess-org/lila.

6/2021 - Present Grokking Vietnam:

Grokking Vietnam is a nonprofit organization dedicated to building and supporting a high-quality community of software engineers in Vietnam.

- Contributor for our newsletter
- Leading a team of five people on Grox project
- Program Director since 7/2022

4/2020 - 3/2023 Senior Software Developer - The Techno Creatives:

- Tyri IntelliLight: A project includes mobile apps and back-end for setting up, controlling and sharing Tyri products with Bluetooth mesh.
 - Responsible for back-end using SpringBoot, Kotlin, Arrow, r2dbc, PostgreSQL, Redis, Test
 Containers.
 - Update API and add Bluetooth Mesh module to Beckon-Android library.
 - Use Kotlin multiplatform mobile and SqlDelight to implement the Database layer for IOS and Android Apps.
- rentr.se A trailers rental service.
 - A part of a back-end team using Rust, Kotlin, GraphQL, RabbitMQ.
- Implement a POC of Divvun Spell Checking plugin for OmegaT app.
 - Rust, Java, Kotlin, JNA
- A part of Android hiring team which includes: Screen candidate profiles, review assignments and technical interviews.

8/2018 - 4/2020 Software Developer - The Techno Creatives:

Starting as an Android developer, I was responsible for the architecture design for most Android projects. Introduced functional programming, MVI architecture and other design patterns to our team. During this period, I started to become a multi-discipline developer by working with different languages and products.

- Axkid Connect Android App
 - Work with firmware team on debugging and protocol
 - Responsible for App architecture and BLE integration.
- Beckon-Android A BLE library for Android.
 - Design and implement the library
 - The library was designed to be used in Axkid Connect Android App and then other teams adopted it for other BLE related projects such as Weret Android App.
- Gut A Git multi repo maintenance CLI tool.
 - The app is being used widely in Divvun organization
- 24rental an MVP of trailer rental service.
 - Implement back-end using NodeJS, Typescript, PostgreSQL

6/2016 - 6/2018 Senior Android Developer - Localift(Remote Position)

Localift was an Australian startup which works with smart cities, companies and communities to deliver trusted shared mobility solutions, reducing congestion, economic costs and environmental impacts.

- The main responsible for the development Android App. App features include: ride tracking, ride scheduling, mapping integration (geocoding, place search, map interactions), friend lists, groups, messaging, push notifications, calendar integration, Facebook integration.
- After May 2017, including the responsibility for maintaining, deploying back-end (nodejs) and IOS app (Swift) after the CTO resigned.

11/2015 - 5/2016 Android Developer - CommonWealth Bank Vietnam

Develop the first MVP version of a banking application for Android which is TymeGlobal now.

1/2015 - 11/2015 Senior Android Developer - Evil Genius Technologies

Develop http://www.followupboss.com app on Android.

9/2013 - 12/2014 Android Developer - Saritasa Vietnam

Various Android projects

5/2011 - 9/2013 Freelancer Android Developer

Various Android projects

11/2009 - 5/2011 Mobile Developer - FPT Software

• Develop games and applications for different mobile platforms in C, C++, J2ME, Android, IOS.

Side Projects and Open Source

Side Projects

Grox: Building an Interpreter in Scala 3 by using functional programming techniques(Following **Crafting Interpreters book**)

Compilers: A place for me to learn/experiment with interpreters/compilers, type theory and functional programming.

RxArrow: RxJava extensions for Arrow's Data Types

Schack: Chess logic library in Scala 3.

Open Source

Arrow - Functional library for Kotlin: I am a contributor and a member of the maintainer commitée.

ScalaChess - Chess API written in Scala. Immutable and free of side effects: I am a maintainer of this library.

Lichess - The second largest internet chess server in the world: Some small bug fixes, mostly related to scalachess.

Programming Languages

As a multi-discipline developer, I am fairly proficient in several programming languages. In the last few years I have been using these programming languages in professional or personal context(in alphabetical order): Elm, Haskell, Java, Javascript, Kotlin, Lua, Python, Rust, Scala 2, Scala 3, Swift, Typescript.

Human Languages

- · Vietnamese (native speaker)
- English (Fluent)

Education

2007-2011 Bachelor of Software Engineering; FPT University (Hanoi - Vietnam)

Academic Honors and Awards

- 2009 Regional ACM/ICPC Competition at Phuket/Thailand Encourage Prize
- 2009 Vietnam National ACM/ICPC Competition Second Prize
- 2008 Vietnam National Mathematics Olympiad for student Third Prize
- 2007 Full Scholarship at FPT University
- 2006 Took part in the Vietnam National Mathematics Olympiad

lenguyenthanh@hotmail.com • +46 73 145 4318 • Gothenburg, Sweden